Every book has a life of its own.
The Ninth Gate is a mystery, thriller, horror film directed by Roman Polanski.
A rare book dealer finds himself at the heart of a string of paranormal events when he is hired to find the last
two copies of a text, The Nine Gates of the Kingdom of Shadows, capable of summoning the Devil.
Dean Corso, played by Johnny Depp.
Boris Balkan, played by Frank Langella.
Liana Telfer, played by Lena Olin.
The Girl, played by Emmanuelle Seigner.
Baroness Kessler, played by Barbara Jefford.
Victor Fargas, played by Jack Taylor.
The Ninth Gate is a 1999 neo-noir horror thriller film
directed, produced, and co-written by Roman Polanski.
An international co-production between the United States, Portugal, France, and Spain, the
film is loosely based upon Arturo Pérez-Reverte's 1993 novel The Club Dumas.
The film stars Johnny Depp as a dealer of rare books who is tasked with
authenticating a 17th-century book that, if used correctly, can summon the Devil.
The premiere showing was at San Sebastián, Spain, on 25 August 1999, a month
before the 47th San Sebastian International Film Festival.
Though critically and commercially unsuccessful in North America, where reviewers compared it unfavorably with Polanski's supernatural
film Rosemary's Baby (1968), The Ninth Gate earned a worldwide gross of $58.4 million against a $38 million budget.
It has since been described as a cult classic.
The film explores themes of hotel, new york city, suicide, library, portugal.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.